International Women's Year Conference Records 1986.0003
Archives and Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Library
International Women's Year Conference Records
1973-1980
Archives and Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Library
1986.0003
2.5 Linear Feet
The Connecticut State conference of the International Women's Year was held at the University of Bridgeport on 11-12 June 1977. The women's conference was sponsored by the National Committee on the Observance of International Women's Year in order to elect delegates to attend the National Conference in Houston in November and to adopt resolutions to present to the National Conference.
History
The Connecticut State conference of the International Women's Year was held at the University of Bridgeport on 11-12 June 1977. The women's conference was sponsored by the National Committee on the Observance of International Women's Year in order to elect delegates to attend the National Conference in Houston in November and to adopt resolutions to present to the National Conference.
Scope and Content
The collection contains correspondence, notes, reports, surveys, membership lists and other documentation of the work of the Connecticut organization and delegates to the International Women's Year Conference. Also included is a film and cassette recordings of the proceedings.
Arrangement
Series I: Connecticut Women's Conference ((1973-1977) is alphabetically arranged by subject. Materials include papers on workshops, Speak-out programs, art exhibits/performances, registration, reports, resolutions, and correspondence.
Series II: National IWY (1975-1980) is also alphabetically arranged with cassettes and a film placed at the end of the collection. The series includes correspondence between the National IWY and the Connecticut Chapter. There are also four boxes of cassettes of live recordings of the National Conference in Houston, Texas, November 1977 and a movie entitled "Decade of Our Destiny."
Custodial History
Elizabeth Spaulding, head of the Connecticut delegation to the 1977 National Women's Conference in Houston requested that Diana Woolis, Director of the UConn Women's Center house the materials in 1986.
Acquisition Information
Diana Woolis>, Director of the UConn Women's Center, transferred the materials to the Archives in the Fall of 1986.
Access
The collection is open and available for research.
Financial Records; Audiocassettes; Fliers (printed matter); Audio visual materials; Administrative records; Bridgeport (inhabited place); Publications (documents); Women; Congresses and conventions; United States (nation); International cooperation; Education; Universities and colleges; Women's rights; Connecticut (state); Correspondence; Texas (state); Feminism
- Series I: Connecticut Women's Conference, undated, 1973-1977
  - Arrangements, undated, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Arts and Artists, undated, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Budget Committee-bills/IWY, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Coordinating Committee, 1975-1977 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Coordinating Committee Minutes, 1976-1977 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Delegates, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Distribution of Attendance, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Final Report, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Final Report, excerpts of, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 9-10)
  - Hispanic Women, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Hispanic Women: Booklets, 1973-1976 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Interoffice memoranda, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Legislators, undated, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Letterhead Samples, undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Letters of Appreciation, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Letters of Complaint, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Media, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Members and Potential Members, 1976-1977 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Miscellaneous Letters, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - News Release, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Norma Corey Towers report, undated (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Opinions, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Original Resolutions, undated, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Panel, undated (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Printer drafts, 1976-1977 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Publications, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Public service announcements, undated (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Registrations sent, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Resolutions, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Resolutions/Leaflets, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Resolutions typed, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Speak-out speakers, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Speakers panel, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Subcommittees, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Veterans benefits, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Workshops, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 38)
- Series II: National IWY, undated, 1975-1980
  - Homemakers in Missouri, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - IWY Legislative Forum, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - IWY Legislative Forum, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - IWY Mexico City, undated (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - IWY Western Europe, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Manual for State & Territorial IWY Coordinating Comm., 1976 (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - National IWY, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - IWY Basic, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - National Women's Conference, (42 Cassettes)
  - "Decade of Our Destiny" (film, 14 min.)